ADRIANA NIEVES

ABOUT

LINKED-IN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adriananieves/

GITHUB:

https://github.com/itsmeadriana

Portfolio

https://www.adriananieves.com

TECH SPECS:

- » JavaScript/JS6
- » HTML/CSS
- » Node.js
- » SQL/Sequelize/MySQL
- » Express.js
- » NoSQL/MongoDB
- » Git
- » React JSX
- » Handlebars

Adriana is a full-stack webdeveloper based in Austin, Texas. Her academic and performance background in classical music makes her a disciplined, precise, and creative asset to any team. Originally from Orlando, Florida, she understands the importance of keeping users happy with their experiences. She is passionate about inclusivity, diversity, and giving back to her community. As a fresh graduate of the Coding Bootcamp, she is excited to build and design web applications that are intuitive, modular, and accessible.

EDUCATION

2021

THE CODING BOOTCAMP, University of Texas - Austin Full-stack web-development

2016 - 2018

MASTER OF MUSIC, Boston University Music Performance

2008 - 2014

BACHELOR OF MUSIC, University of Central Florida: Burnett Honors College Music Performance.

Professional Work experience

OPERA ORLANDO (2019 – 2021)

STUDIO ARTIST, covered mainstage roles, performed for outreach events, participated in and helped lead masterclasses, posed in photoshoots to promote the upcoming season

ORANGE COUNTY PUBLIC SCHOOLS (2019)

MEDIA CLERK II, high school media clerk; "face" of the library; helped students with library books and textbooks; completed inventory for library books and textbooks; managed twenty student assistants; tutored students in writing; fulfilled administrative role in the media center; miscellaneous housekeeping

BERKLEE COLLEGE OF MUSIC BOOKSTORE (2018)

BOOKSELLER/CASHIER, customer service role; stocked inventory; provided a friendly face to students and connected them with their needs

PRIVATE WRITING AND LITERATURE TUTOR (2006 – PRESENT)

Help students write essays from thesis writing to outline and to final draft; copy-editing; correct grammar and spelling; teach short stories, classic novels, and help students extract themes and symbols, and most importantly, develop critical thinking skills